For years, obviously, your unfinished goal was to win a Grand Slam.
多年来 你的心愿是赢下大满贯
Now that you've got two,
如今你已拿到两座
does the goal, number one in the world, occupy that headspace?
世界第一会占据你的心思吗？
Again, I think, yeah, it's definitely a talking point. There's no secret about it.
这肯定是个话题 没什么好隐瞒的
It's definitely a talking point for everybody at the moment.
现在大家都在谈论它
But for me, yeah, I'm motivated to keep playing.
但对我来说 我有动力继续打下去
I'm motivated to keep fighting for good things, hopefully.
继续为好结果拼下去 希望如此
10月6日 辛纳宣布结束赛季
今年的积分榜上
兹维列夫领先800分
年终第一几乎到手 可他
还没当过一天世界第1
可今年 他和阿尔卡拉斯 辛纳
德约交手7次 一场没赢
没赢过三强的年终第一 算数吗？
其中5场输给辛纳 包括温网决赛
澳网半决赛输给阿尔卡拉斯
北京1/4决赛输给德约
A moment of brilliance from Carlos Alcaraz secures a place in his very first Australian Open final.
阿尔卡拉斯神来一笔 首进澳网决赛
Jannik Sinner seals his spot in a first Monte Carlo final.
辛纳锁定首个蒙特卡洛决赛席位
但这一年 不只有失利
法网决赛 他5盘击败科博利
拿到第一座大满贯
How about that! How about that!
太精彩了！太精彩了！
Sweet set-up, another forehand, crushed.
漂亮的铺垫 又一记正手 重重压下
Four sets of compelling tennis to finish up Wimbledon 2026.
四盘扣人心弦 为2026温网收官
A final to remember.
一场值得铭记的决赛
Game, set and match, Zverev. Three sets to one: 6-3, 7-6, 5-7, 6-2.
比赛结束 兹维列夫3比1获胜
Zverev doesn't know he's won. He doesn't even know he's won.
兹维列夫还不知道自己赢了
There you go.
这下知道了
He really didn't know. He was so focused in on just holding serve.
他真的不知道 一心只想保发
He didn't know he was at the finish line, and he finishes off Ben Shelton in four sets
没意识到已到终点 四盘击败谢尔顿
and wins his second major of the year, his first US Open.
拿下年度第二座大满贯 首个美网
We went 30 years without winning a Grand Slam title,
我们30年没拿过大满贯
and now we won two in a span of three months.
如今三个月拿了两座
I think God has seen how hard we worked, how much we suffered, how much pain we went through,
上天看见了我们的努力 煎熬和伤痛
and I think 2026 is the outcome of all the years that... that happened before, so...
2026年是此前所有岁月的结果
He's done it again.
他又一次做到了
Novak Djokovic.
德约科维奇
There's something about this place,
这座球场有种特别的力量
and there is something about this man.
这个男人也有特别之处
The unbeaten record here in Beijing continues.
他在北京的不败纪录仍在延续
答案在规则里
排名每周一更新
只算最近52周
赛季结束时排第一 就是年终第一
积分只看打到第几轮
大满贯冠军2000分
对手是谁并不影响
他今年两座大满贯
就是4000分
这套电脑排名
始于1973年8月23日
第一位世界第1 是纳斯塔塞
It's a very, very exclusive club, being number one in the world,
世界第一是极少数人的俱乐部
and I think it's the ultimate goal we have, you know, 52 weeks of consistent tennis.
终极目标 52周稳定的网球
可年终第一 并不总是年度最佳
一九七五到七八年 1982年
1989年 两个称号都不是同一个人
1977年 维拉斯拿下法网和美网
美网决赛击败康纳斯
可按当年的平均分算法
年终第一仍是康纳斯
七四到七八年 他连续5年年终第一
1989年 贝克尔拿下温网和美网
两次击败伦德尔 当选年度最佳
年终第一仍是伦德尔
No way.
不可能
Match point. Becker has it all to do.
赛点 贝克尔必须全力挽救
I don't believe it.
难以置信
Well, this will surely be remembered as the match and the tiebreak that had everything.
这场比赛和抢七注定被铭记
从2000年起 年度最佳球员
每年都是年终第一
年终第一 有时要拼到最后一站
2016年总决赛决赛 穆雷对德约
谁赢 谁就是年终第一
Murray wins!
穆雷赢了！
Murray wins it all!
穆雷包揽一切！
He's champion of the Barclays ATP World Tour Finals,
他是ATP年终总决赛冠军
and he's created history
他创造了历史
by becoming only the 17th player in the history of the game
成为史上第17位
to be crowned year-end world No. 1.
加冕年终世界第一的球员
Well, it's obviously the crown of the season, you know, finishing the year as number one in the world.
以世界第一结束赛季 是一季的王冠
I think it's a dream of every tennis player.
这是每个网球运动员的梦想
It's one of the most difficult things to do in our sport.
也是这项运动里最难做到的事之一
Obviously, you know, winning Grand Slams and being number one in the world are probably the pinnacles of the sport.
大满贯和世界第一是运动巅峰
But you win two majors in a season,
一个赛季赢两座大满贯
it's hard not to be picked as the man of the year,
很难不当选年度最佳
and I think if you asked any of the players,
如果问任何一位球员
they'd probably pick majors over world number one,
多半会选大满贯而非世界第一
and he might actually be able to do both.
而他也许能两样都拿到
两座大满贯
加上几乎到手的年终第一
明年 他能赢下三强吗？